这份报告披露了从未被了解的情况
Something they had never seen, which liberated a yellow,
有关恐怖的暴力情况
very pungent and acrid vapor.
在缅甸 态度强硬的军政府
The actions of the hard-line mliitary regime.
国际社会对其强硬政权行径的担忧 与日俱增
are the cause of increasing international concern.
该政权为自己所作予以辩护
The regime crushes all dissent.
缅甸西部的一些族群正被镇压
Ethnic groups are being oppressed in the east of the country,
外国记者很少能够进入此地采访
and foreign journalists are rarely…
据称 缅甸使用了早期化学武器
…claim tonight that some form of chemical weapon.
施行灭绝平民百姓
has been used in Burma by mliitary rulers…
引起了大众的不满情绪
…has led to the national uprising.
几千人在街上被屠杀
Thousands took to the streets and thousands were killed…
许多和平抗议的僧侣被杀害
In Burma, many peaceful protesting monks have been killed,
不是被活埋就是被淹死
some burned alive, and others drowned.
外国新闻工作者也不幸遇害
Foreign journalists have been shot and killed.
无数村庄被摧毁
As thousands of villages have been destroyed,
强奸和私刑每天在发生
rape and torture are a daliy occurrence.
缅甸埋的地雷数量全球第一
In Burma, there are more land mines than anywhere in the world.
年轻人被殴打并强行征召入伍
Young men are beaten and forced into the army,
许多人只有十二岁
many as young as 12 years old.
斩首随处可见
Beheadings and mutliations are commonplace.
克伦族人大多顺从
The Karen people, comprised mostly of poor Christian farmers,
贫穷的农民基督教徒刻意被处决
have been singled out for extermination.
缅甸军政府觊觎
The ruling mliitary government.
克伦族的自然资源已久
wants the abundant natural resources on Karen land.
缅甸政府军针对克伦族的血腥行动
The bloody Burmese mliitary campaign against the Karen people.
持续了几乎60年
has been going on for almost 60 years,
是世界上最长的内战
the longest running civli war in the world.
《第一滴血4》
你看 这两条蛇 他们是暹罗眼镜蛇或普通眼镜蛇
Two snake that you see, they are Siamese cobra or common cobra.
（泰国 美索镇）
他们不是眼镜蛇王或射毒眼镜蛇
He is not king cobra and not spitting cobra.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
你去哪里了
袋子给他
我们还需要一只蟒蛇 你去抓来
眼镜蛇太多了
滚开 行吗
Fuck off, okay?
它们还是有毒性
They still have fang and still have poison.
他是很小 最危险 位居第一的毒蛇
He is small, dangerous, number one.
第二是眼镜蛇王
King cobra number two.
这是射毒眼镜蛇
And now spitting cobra.
他会射毒液向你的双眼
He can spit poison to your eye.
一种颜色
One color.
他是非常非常危险的毒蛇 在泰国是最毒的毒蛇
He's very, very dangerous. Number one in Thailand.
千万要小心
Careful, my friend.
看起来是危险的工作
Looks like dangerous work.
我是 麦可·伯内特 能谈谈吗
I'm Michael Burnett. Do you have some time to talk?
不会耽搁太久 我保证
Won't take long, I promise.
有人说可以找你租船
I was told it might be possible to rent your boat.
有意愿吗
We'd like to do that.
我们要去河上游
Is that possible? We need to get upriver.
- 去哪里 - 缅甸境内
- Where you going? - Into Burma.
缅甸是战区
Burma's a war zone.
嗯 外界是这么说的 说是种族屠杀还差不多
Well, that's what people call it, but it's more like genocide than war.
这是我第五次进去了 我们都明白进去的风险
Anyway, this will be my fifth trip in, so we are aware of all the risks.
我不去北边
I don't go that far north.
情况是这样的
Let me explain our situation.
我们隶属在科罗拉多的泛亚洲牧师团
Our church is part of a Pan-Asian ministry located in Colorado,
我们是今年度的义工
and we're all volunteers who around this time of year.
要为克伦部落的人带去医药和救治
bring in medical supplies, medical attention,
祈祷书和我们的支持
prayer books and support for the Karen tribes people.
听说你比任何人都熟悉这条河
People say you know the river better than anyone.
骗人的
Well, they lied.
我们希望能雇用你
So, what I'm asking is that we compensate you.
只花你几小时时间
for a few hours of your time.
就可以帮助我们改善难民生活
It will help change people's lives.
- 你们有带任何武器吗 - 当然没有
- Are you bringing in any weapons? - Of course not.
那你们什么都改变不了
You're not changing anything.
那你
Well…
难道要让世界继续这样 而不管吗
It's thinking like that that keeps the world the way it is.
该死的世界
Fuck the world.
- 我们走吧 - 为什么
- Let's go. - Why?
他没兴趣 我们走吧
He's not interested. Let's just go.
- 让我试试 - 不 莎拉
- Let me try. - No, Sarah…
你说过这是唯一的办法
No, didn't you say it was the only way up there?
- 我知道 - 我们也没什么可损失 是吧
- I know I did… - All right, then what do we have to lose?
- 我和他说说 - 就让我试试 麦可
- I talked to the man… - Just let me try, Michael.
- 莎拉 - 不
- Sarah… - Please.
你好
Hello?
我是 莎拉·米勒
I'm Sarah Miller.
希望你不介意我又回来找你
I hope you don't mind me coming back here.
刚才你和他说话的那个人
The man that you were talking to…
我没和任何人说话
I wasn't talking to anybody.
好吧
All right.
那刚才和你说话的人
The man that was talking to you.
问你是否愿意借船带我们去上游
asked if we could hire you to take us up the river.
- 你不愿意 为什么 - 我帮不上忙
- You said no. Why? - Can't help you out.
可以听听你拒绝的理由吗
Well, if you have good reasons, would you mind if I heard them?
回家去吧
Go home.
你不应该在这里
You shouldn't be in here.
你可以重新考虑吗
Would you reconsider?
你看 我不知道你的一切
Look, I don't know anything about you,
你好像也不关心发生的问题
and it seems like you don't care to know anything about us.
莎拉
Sarah.
你住这么近 这里都这么多难民
But you live so close to what's going on over here.
你真的无动于衷吗
I mean, doesn't it bother you at all?
说过了帮不上忙
It's not my business.
莎拉 我们应该离开了
Sarah, we should go.
你认为人就放在这里 死无理由
Do you believe that people are put here to die for no reason?
或相信时间就可以改变一切
Or believe in giving time to something other than yourself?
我的意思是 你相信吗
I mean, do you believe in anything?
你真的应该走了
You really ought to go.
这男的并不在乎 我们再想想办法
The man doesn't care. We'll figure something out.
（缅甸 塔克和德村-巴本行政区）
求你了 别抓我儿子
这些孩子是我们的士兵了
他们现在属于我了
要是有人想把他们救回去 就把你们整个村子烧了
要是你们敢去找克伦反抗军帮忙 我就割掉你们的舌头
要是你们敢反抗我 我就用你们的肠子喂你们
听我 信我 怕我
怎么又回来了
Why'd you come back?
等你啊
Waiting for you.
- 说过了帮不上忙 - 为什么
- I told you before, I can't help you. - Why?
我不想要
I don't want to.
- 你朋友在哪里 - 酒店
- Where are your friends? - At the hotel.
我可以照顾自己
I can take care of myself.
- 真的 - 是
- Is that so? - Yes.
- 我知道你不喜欢我们 - 我可没说过
- I know you don't like us. - I never said that.
看上来却是这样
Well, it looks that way.
我们必须去帮助那些人
We need to go and help these people.
谁要你的帮助
Who are you helping?
他们或者是你
Them or you?
- 有关系吗 - 当然有
- Does it matter? - Yeah, it matters.
他们
Them.
不要让生活留白
There's nothing missing in our lives back home.
我们来这儿就是为了改变现状
We're here to make a difference.
我们坚信每个生命都是珍贵的
We believe all lives are special.
- 有些是 有些不是 - 真的吗
- Some lives, some, no. - Really?
如果每个人都这么想 那什么都改变不了
If everyone thought like you, nothing would ever change.
任何事都改变不了
Nothing does change.
当然不是 没什么是不会变的
Of course it does. Nothing stays the same.
好好的过你的生活吧
Live your life, 'cause you got a good one.
那正是我尝试做的
It's what I'm trying to do.
不 你尝试做的是改变它原来的样子
No, what you're trying to do is change what is.
- 什么样子 - 我们像动物
- And what is? - That we're like animals.
战斗的血液在你身上流窜 别抗拒
It's in the blood. It's natural.
和平 这是一个意外
Peace, that's an accident.
就是这样
It's what is.
当你被压迫 杀人就像是呼吸一样的简单
When you're pushed, killing is as easy as breathing.
当某个地方停止杀戮 另一个地方却再开始
Then the killing stops in one place and it starts in another,
因为你是为了你的国家去杀戮
but that's okay 'cause you're killing for your country.
但它不是你国家的要求 它只是某些高层的意愿
But it ain't your country who's asking. It's a few men up top who want it.
先人开例 后人顺从
Old men start it, young men fight it.
没有赢家 每个人都在过程中死亡
Nobody wins, everybody in the middle dies.
也没有人告诉真相
And nobody tells the truth.
上帝会再让一切消失
God's gonna make all that go away?
不要浪费你的生命 我做到了
Don't waste your life. I did.
回家去吧
Go home.
真的 回去吧
Really. Go home.
- 你在乎 - 什么
- You care. - What?
还有些事是你关心的
You care.
如果你不关心 你可以带我们去那边
Because if you didn't, you would have taken us there,
赚取金钱就算了
taken the money and be done with it.
但是你并没有这么做
But you didn't do that.
可能
Maybe…
或许你失去了对人的信念
Maybe you've lost your faith in people,
但一定还有些事是你相信的
but you must still be faithful to something.
相信我 我害怕
Believe me, I'm scared.
我热爱我的生活 我不想失去它
And I love my life and I don't want to lose it.
但尝试去拯救生命 并不浪费人生 是吗
But trying to save a life isn't wasting your life, is it?
你能帮我们吗
Will you help us?
好吧
All right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
像那些如此邪恶的人 终究会输的
As bad as these people are, they will eventually lose.
他们不能一直跟联合阵线对抗
They can't keep it up against a united front. They can't.
时间会证明一切的 但同时
I mean, time alone will tell, but in the meantime,
我们必须团结一致
we just have to help hold it together.
前几天 我读了
I mean, just the other day, I read…
抱歉
Excuse me.
莎拉 你要去哪里
Sarah, where are you going?
和他聊聊
To talk to him.
他可能不想被烦
Well, he probably wants his privacy.
麦可 你不该无视他的
Michael, you shouldn't ignore him.
- 他帮了我们 - 我们已经付他钱了
- He's helping us. - He's been paid.
他什么都没拿
He didn't take anything.
再次感谢你 谢谢帮我们 真的 我们所有人都感谢你
Thank you, again, for doing this. Really. From all of us.
这里永远看起来都是一样
It's like the same view goes on forever.
在这里是如此的空旷
It's so empty out here.
它只是看起来这样
It just looks that way.
你看 你还没跟我们说你的名字呢
You know, you never told us your name.
- 约翰 - 约翰
- John. - John.
- 在这里住了很久吗 - 好久了
- Lived here a long time? - Long time.
- 你从哪来的 - 亚利桑纳州的包威市
- Where you from? - Bowie, Arizona. Small place.
那边你都做些什么呢
What'd you do there?
主要都是农场养马的
Worked horses, mainly.
- 为何离开呢 - 我被征召去打越战
- Why'd you leave? - I got drafted in Nam.
- 很久了 - 已经有好多年了
- Long time ago. - Long time ago. Lot of years.
你就一直待下来了
And you just stayed?
一言难尽
It's complicated.
- 家里还有亲人吗 - 父亲吧 不太清楚
- You have family back home? - Father maybe. I don't know.
难道你不好奇家乡有什么变化吗
Aren't you curious to see how things might've changed back home?
回去也要有个理由
Got to have a reason for that.
- 你从事什么工作 - 老师 第六级
- What do you do stateside? - I teach. Sixth grade.
怎么了
What?
现在我终于了解为何你 总是这么多问题
Now I know why you ask so many questions.
- 还有多远啊 - 还要几个小时
- Any idea how much longer? - Yeah, just a few more hours.
也许我们应该让这男人有自己的空间了
Maybe we should give the man his space.
我们谈谈时间表 好吗
We should go over the schedule, okay?
好
Okay.
忙回自己的事情 它可是个好人
We're engaged. He's a good man.
那可好
That's good.
我知道你以为你自己是孤独的 但总有某些东西会推动你
I know you think you live alone out here, but there's always something pushing you.
- 怎么回事 他们是谁 - 缅甸的海盗
- What is it? Who are they? - Burmese pirates.
都坐下 别出声
Tell everyone to stay down, don't make a sound.
- 他们是谁 - 没事 没事
- Who are they? - It's all right, it's all right.
- 只是… - 别说话
- Just keep… - Don't talk!
- 还有人吗 - 或许
- Any more of them? - Maybe.
你们想怎么做
What do you wanna do?
继续前进 我们说好的
We should keep going. We made a commitment.
- 你想要怎么做 - 我们是一起的
- What do you wanna do? - We're a group here.
如果他们是要这船
If they wanna vote…
- 坐下 - 如果他们是要钱
- Sit down! - If it's money they want…
安静 头低下
Nobody talks. Heads down.
把头低下 别直视他们
Keep your heads down and nobody look them in the eye,
他们会杀光你们
or they'll kill you.
你们有灯 快打亮
我要看清楚你们这些笨蛋 快
这一区河域归我们管
你们想通过
我们可以马上干掉你们
你们为何不尊重我们
我尊重你们
我要你们船上的所有财物
你们这些白种笨蛋要去哪里
送药给病人
看这里
那是女人吗
把她带过来
拿走财物 别动她
给我闭嘴
把她带过来
我们会交出钱
还用说 把她带过来
我们会交出全部的钱
可恶
站起来 婊子
最后一次 把她带过来
否则就杀光你们
不
No!
你做了什么好事
What did you do?
我们来这是为了停止杀戮的
We came here to help stop the killing!
你凭什么 怎么能
Who are you to…
- 你算老几 - 放开他
- Who are you? - Let him go!
他们会强奸她至死 再砍掉你们的头
They would've raped her 50 times, and cut your heads off.
我们回去
We're going back!
不 我们不能回去
No. No, we shouldn't go back.
- 你想干嘛 - 不能带我们回去
- What are you doing? - Don't take us back.
- 这里发生的事很恐怖 - 我们就快到了
- Look what just happened! - We got through it.
- 我们明年再回来 - 我们就快到了
- We'll come back next year. - We are so close.
麦可 这是你的主意 我们承诺过的
Michael, this was your idea. We made a commitment.
我知道你不会认同我们所为
I know you don't believe in what we're doing,
但这就是我们的生活
but it's our life, our choice.
拜托 求你 约翰
Please. Please, John.
求求你
Please.
你们改变不了任何事的
You're not going to change anything.
回去坐好
Go sit down.
好了
It's all right.
我们回程会走陆路
We'll be taking the overland route on the way back,
你不用等我们
so there's no need to wait around.
我会呈报这件事
I have to report this.
我知道你觉得自己做的对 但是杀人永远都是不对的
I know you think what you did was right, but taking a life is never right.
我不知道该说些什么
I don't know what to say.
或许你什么都不必说
Then you shouldn't say anything, should you?
（劳佬村）
嘿
Hey.
你做了什么
What did you do?
好 好
Good, good.
籍着力量 穿过他的灵魂 进入你的内心
Through his spirit in your inner being.
这样主与信念就能在你的心中长存
So Christ may dwell in your hearts with faith.
我祈祷
And I pray…
你们将与我们一起获得力量
…you may have the power together…
嗯 我试试看 能不能修好
Let me see if I can fix this little problem, okay?
嘿 好啊
Okay.
嘿
Hey, you.
拿绷带给我好吗
Hand me one of those bandages?
好的
Okay.
谢了
Thank you.
没事的
Okay.
- 快出去 - 他们怎么办
- Get out of here! - What about them?
快走 我带他们
Go on! Take them!
或许你对人失去了信任
Maybe you've lost your faith in people,
但是你还是很在乎
but you must still be faithful to something.
还是会对某人关心
Still care about something.
（缅甸国家和平和发展委员会 轻步兵第360营）
把那个带出去关到猪舍
喂 呼叫乌鸦 请回话 乌鸦
Company leader calling Raven. Come on, Raven.
我是谁 是你造就了我
What am I? You made me this way.
一个天生热血的战士
A full-blooded combat soldier.
你就是不肯结束它
You just don't turn it off.
说话啊 约翰
Talk to me, Johnny.
你就是不肯结束它
You just don't turn it off!
- 结束了 - 没有事情会结束
- It's over. - Nothing is over!
什么时候你才能回来呢
When are you gonna come full circle?
我知道你为什么来这 约翰
I know the reasons you're here, John.
你难道不想看看家乡变成什么样了吗
Aren't you curious to see how things might've changed back home?
你已经造成够多的伤害了
You've done enough damage.
除非你与自己妥协
You're always going to be tearing away at yourself.
并回到原点
untli you come to terms with what you are.
否则你将一直被自己的恐惧驱使
Untli you come full circle.
所以你要一直待下去吗
So you're just going to stay here forever?
- 约翰 - 我要回家
- John! - I wanna go home!
约翰·蓝波
John Rambo!
约翰
John?
约翰·蓝波
John Rambo?
我叫 亚瑟·马许
My name is Arthur Marsh,
科罗拉多基督会的牧师
pastor of the Christ Church of Colorado.
我得和你谈谈 事关紧急
I need to talk with you. It's very important.
不然我不会在这种天气来访的
I wouldn't come here like this if it wasn't.
援助小队离开的那天早上
The morning of the day the group left,
麦可·伯内特 通知了我 他们从这里出发的
Michael Burnett notified me that they were traveling from this location.
- 出什么事了 - 事实上 没人知道
- What happened? - No one knows exactly.
他们本该10天前就返回 到现在都没出现
They were supposed to return 10 days ago, but they never came back.
我寻求大使馆的帮助 但他们无能为力
I requested help from the embassy, but they can't help.
在缅甸 在这时机 真的没办法
Not in Burma, and not in time.
你怎知他们还活着
How do you know they're alive?
因为我们联络上了克伦自由组织
Because we've been in contact with the Karen freedom fighters.
他们说知道小队成员被带到哪了
who say they think they know where they were taken.
大使馆给我一个退役美军的名字
And I was given the name of an ex-military American local from the embassy.
说他们一伙在这方面很有经验
who put me in touch with men who say they have experience.
在这方面很有经验
in this part of the world.
雇佣兵吧
Mercenaries.
是的
Yes.
我别无选择
I don't have any other choice.
你知道正确的地点
You know the exact spot. We need you to take these men.
我们需要你把这些人带到那里去
to where you let our people off.
他们何时要出发
When are they ready to leave?
由你决定
When you are.
你觉得你不应该帮得上忙吗
Aren't you gonna say something?
- 我不明白 - 你应该会明白
- I don't understand. - You should.
你的意思是祈祷
You mean a prayer?
不是为我 是为他们
Not for me, for them.
是
Yes.
主
Lord,
让我成为你手中的傀儡吧
make me your instrument of peace.
哪里有仇恨 就让我把爱带到那里
Where there is hatred, let me bring love.
哪里有伤害 就让我把宽恕带到那里
Where there is injury, pardon.
哪里有疑问 就让我把信念带到那里
Where there is doubt, faith.
哪里有绝望 就让我把希望带到那里
Where there is despair, hope.
哪里有黑暗 就让我把光明带到那里
Where there is darkness, light.
哪里有悲伤 就让我把喜悦带到那里
Where there is sadness, joy.
当需要安慰时不需费力地寻求安慰
Grant that I may not seek to be consoled as to console,
少求被了解 但求了解人
to be understood as to understand,
少求爱 但求全心付出爱
to be loved as to love,
因为我们得到了 所以我们应该付出
for it is in giving that we receive.
当我们面临死亡我们会在来世重新醒过来
It is in dying that we awake to eternal life.
看看这鬼地方 只有他妈的猴子 才会住在这吧
Look at this fucking place. Only a fucking ape would live here.
我他妈的来这干嘛
What the fuck am I doing here?
嘿 别再讲那些屁话
Hey, knock that shit off.
你不欣赏文艺吗
En-Joo don't like the arts.
- 我不欣赏大便啦 - 但我欣赏你姐姐 迪亚兹
- En-Joo don't like shit. - I like your sister, Diaz.
她喜欢智障
She got a thing for retards.
那个牧师跟你说了什么
So what did the Reverend say to you?
一些笨蛋走丢了
Some shit about part of his flock going missing.
我说那是
I said to him, "Look, mate.
乱闯缅甸的结果
"That's what you get when you go trespassing into fucking Burma.
爱管闲事就是这种下场
"That's what you get when you go sniffing around other people's garbage."
那里的将军们制造的毒品
You know, those generals in there are making a lot of money.
比地球上任何地方都多
Millions cranking out meth more than any other place on the fucking planet.
唬烂
Bullshit.
- 赚上百万啊 - 白痴
- Millions, moron. - Hell, yeah, man.
不然你以为他们拿什么养军队
How do you think they pay for that shit army?
去他妈的将军 都他妈的是瘾君子
Fucking generals, biggest junkies of all of them.
这很崇高的 路易士
It's noble, Lewis.
你说什么
You what?
那些手无寸铁地进入战区的人
Those people going in there with no weapons,
只带了书籍和药品 很崇高
just books and meds. It's noble.
学童
Oi, School Boy.
凭着崇高理想来淌浑水
You stick your noble nose into other people's business,
下场不是很惨 就是死路一条
you get fucked up or you get dead.
我是为了前妻及三个孩子 才来冒险
The only reason I'm doing this is for an ex-wife and three kids.
以后 我绝不过这种卖命日子
And after this shit is over,
我可不想还没到达就老死
you can shove that soldiering right up your arse.
嘿 船夫
Oi, boat man. Come on, chop-chop!
早去才能早回啊
The quicker we get there, the quicker we get back.
可恶的传道士
Lousy God-squadders.
他们来这里 滔滔不绝地布道
They come over here spouting all that shit,
还梦想全世界跟他们相亲相爱
and they expect the whole world to work like their fucking neighborhood.
当然不可能
Well, it doesn't.
所以他们派了个魔鬼
So they send in the devil.
来做上帝的工作 不是很讽刺吗
to do God's work. It's ironic, isn't it?
我是不是让你觉得很无聊
Am I boring you, mate?
还是旅程的关系 让你紧张了吗
What, is it… Is it the trip? Has it got you nervous?
你该感谢这次行动
'Cause, really, you should appreciate the action.
你明白我的意思吗
You know what I mean?
总比抓蛇强
Got to be better than looking at the arse end of a snake.
哦 天啊
Oh, dear.
你是个狠角色是吧
You really are an uptight bastard, aren't you?
少用怪眼神瞪我了 我见过各种人
You can drop the 1, 000-yard stare. I've seen it all before,
你唬不了我
and I'm not impressed.
他是传统老派的英国SAS特种部队
He's old school SAS.
第一流的狂热军人
They're first-rate soldiers, but total egomaniacs.
我们是SBS出身的 我们不这么重手
Now, us SBS boys, we're not so heavy-handed.
我们喜欢用脑 明白吗
We like to use our brains. You know what I mean?
他们叫我“学童”
They call me School Boy.
这名字从狙击学校开始就跟着我了
The name stuck with me since sniper school.
不管我杀了多少人 我的同伴还是用这名字叫我
And me mates won't stop calling me it no matter how many people I shoot.
你究竟要拿我们怎样
What do you want from us?
一大一小 在搞笑是吧
One man and a kid. You gotta be fucking joking.
反抗军就这么一点人
This all the rebels they put up?
我不怎么喜欢这地方
I'm not liking it.
我们身在丛林当中 什么都不妙
You're in a fucking jungle, puss nuts. There's nothing to like.
你好啊
How you doing?
我叫班恩 他是泰
My name is Myint. This is Tha.
- 就你们俩 - 对
- Is this it? - Yes.
- 这小孩怎么回事 - 他是个敏锐的追踪者
- What's up with the kid, man? - He good tracker.
我们不需要狗屁追踪者 是需要向导
We don't need a tracker. We need a fucking guide.
你知道正确地点吧
You know the exact location, right?
向西10公里朝北 抄捷径只要六公里
Ten kilometers west, two north, six to a walk.
- 有多少士兵 - 大概有一百个
- How many soldiers? - Hundred, maybe.
- 一百个 - 没说错吧
- Hundred? - What'd he say?
明天还会增援更多新兵
More new soldiers come tomorrow.
虽然我是个白人老粗 但我还会算数
Yeah, I know I'm just a white trash grunt, but I can count.
一百个步兵怎么打
Fuck fucking with 100 strong.
行了 把话说明白
All right, all right, all right. Let's get this straight.
我们不跟人交战
We don't engage anybody.
如果能救出那些志工 那正好
If we can extract these people, good.
但得速战速决 不然我们就闪人
But it's in, out, clean, or we fuck off.
有人可以告诉我船夫要干嘛吗
Somebody wanna tell me what the boat man's doing?
你为什么不跟船待在一起
Hey, why ain't you waiting with the boat?
我的人会在船上
My men are staying with the boat.
是你的船 你就要待在那
You're the boat man. You stay with the boat.
- 我不会拖累你们 - 对 你不会
- I won't slow you down. - Yeah, I know you won't.
- 我们又不是去远足 - 就信他吧
- It's not a fucking nature hike. - Believe that.
- 他可以掩护我们 - 他是船夫 他就得顾船
- He can hang with me at the back. - Hey, hey, he stays here.
他就要跟船待在一起
He's the boat man. He stays with the fucking boat.
我要白人顾船 不要土人
I want a white man on, and not some fucking dink.
谁有炸药 图斯托
Now who's got explosives? Tombstone?
- 没有 - 我有一些塑胶炸药和雷管
- None. - A pound of C-4 and primer.
我一个定向地雷
I got a claymore.
很好 我们走吧
All right, let's get on with it.
走吧 前进
Come on, move, move.
- 这是什么鬼 - 高脚炸弹
- What the fuck is that? - Called Tallboy bomb.
英国佬在二战时投下的
English drop in World War ll.
你们的人 就在这里被掳走
Your people taken from here.
天啊 真是不堪入目
Man, I have seen some shit.
老兄 简直是惨不忍睹
Brother, I ain't never seen no shit like this.
军队来过了 他们杀光一切
Armies come. Kill everything.
并弃尸以示警告
Leave our dead here as warning.
泰 快回家 快
不只这样
He see enough.
到处布满地雷
Mine everywhere.
小心你们脚下
Watch where you walking.
- 好吧 我们继续前进 - 有什么用
- All right, let's move on. - To what?
他们连狗都杀 那些人死定了
They even killed the fucking dogs. Those people are dead.
我也这么认为
I'm with En-Joo.
我们至少得去确定
We at least have to go and have a look-see, check it out.
我同意 至少侦查一下
I'm with you. Let's check it out.
侦查个鸟 他们有上百个士兵耶
Check what? They're 100 strong.
喂 我们拿钱做事
Hey, we took the man's money.
嘿 冷静点
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
冷静
Just calm down, calm down.
我们去 看情况如何
We'll go there, and we'll see what's what.
只要不对劲 有任何动静 我们就闪人
But if anything's wrong, anything at all, we'll leave.
同意吗
All right?
好吧
Yeah.
- 好 - 很好
- All right. - Good.
- 走哪边 - 这边
- Which way? - This way.
是军队 快躲起来
Army! Go! Go!
要开枪吗
I'm going to fire on them.
不要 不 他们如果没有回营
No! They don't make it back from wherever the hell they came from,
我们就曝光了
man, they are on to us.
你拿着钱
我赌这个挺到最后
他们在搞什么鬼
What the fuck are they doing, man?
他们多长时间能被发现
3个小时 或者4个
船夫 你是何方神圣
Who are you, boat man? Where'd you learn to kill like that?
我们走
Let's move.
走 这些家伙们到时候没回去
They're gonna come hunting our asses down.
我们会被追杀
when these guys don't show up.
都是因为这些军人没回营
I got people to live for, man.
我们不需要淌浑水 我们回船上去
We don't need this shit. We're going back to the boat.
不可以 你不能
No, you're not.
你说什么
What did you say?
我不管你是谁
I don't give a fuck who you are.
有种再说一次 我发誓
You say another word and I swear on my kids' eyes.
我会杀了你
I'll kill you.
走吧
Let's go.
嘿
Whoa! Hey, hey!
你不能走
You're not going anywhere.
这里没有人想死
And there isn't one of us that doesn't want to be someplace else,
这是我们所该做的 代表了我们是谁
but this is what we do, who we are.
苟且偷生
Live for nothing,
还是死得其所
or die for something.
你自己决定
Your call.
你怎么想
对
上路吧
Let's move.
一但学童到了塔上 我们只有15分钟
Once School Boy's on the tower, we got 15 minutes.
对表 现在是1点45分
Set your watches to 1:45. In, out, no waiting around for nobody.
我们在塔台集合 逾时不候
We meet at the base of the tower.
- 都准备好了 - 好了
- All set? - Yeah.
好
Set.
我们进去了
We're in.
行动
Go.
别出声
Don't talk. We're getting you out.
- 那女孩在哪里 - 她在那边
- Where's the girl? - She's over there.
松绑他 我会再回来
You untie him. We'll be back for you.
这里
Here.
猪舍旁有两个士兵
There's two of them in the cage, near the pigs.
- 干掉他们 - 收到
- Get them. - Got it.
- 快 快 - 莎拉呢
- Come on, come on. - Do you have Sarah?
闭嘴 快走
Shut up, come on.
求你 不要
Please, no. No.
我们还找不到 一分钟
We can't find shit. One minute.
- 有一个在里面 - 放弃吧
- There's one of them in there. - Leave them.
- 你先离开 - 他们真的这么重要吗 船夫
- You leave. - What the fuck are they to you, boat man?
闭嘴 快走
Run.
- 我们走 - 船夫呢
- Let's move. - Where's the boat man?
- 还有莎拉呢 - 15分钟已过
- And Sarah. - Fifteen minutes. That's the deal.
- 咱们走 - 走吧
- We're leaving. - Let's go!
- 再等5分钟 - 免谈
- Five more minutes. - Bullshit.
他知道计划的
He knew the deal.
我们要共进退
Hey, we came together, we fucking leave together!
- 随便你 命是你自己的 我们走 - 没她我不走
- Your life. Let's go. - Not without her!
救你的不是上帝 是我们
God didn't save your life, we did.
如果你再拿你的生命去冒险
And if you risk your life one more time,
我会在这里杀了你
I will fucking take your life right here.
现在给我起来
Now fucking get up.
起来 走
Get up. Move!
这边
This way.
没事了
It's all right. I got you.
我们离开这里 来
We're getting out of here. Come on.
- 他们在哪里 - 他们从园林那个方向离开了
- Where are they? - They took off that way into the garden.
他们确定知道怎么走
They must know another way out.
离天亮还有一个小时 走回原路
We got an hour till the daylight. We got to backtrack.
这边
This way.
- 拉上来 - 什么事
- Pull up. - What's wrong?
- 让我看看 - 不 我不想拖慢你们
- Lift your foot. - No, I don't wanna slow you down.
抬起你的脚
Lift your foot.
她不可能这样走下去
She's not making it like this.
我不想因为我脚伤的关系害你们被抓
I don't want you to get caught because of me.
歇一歇
Let's move out.
我觉得一切都是我的错
I feel like all this is my fault.
这是全部人都会犯的错
It's everybody's fault.
我只想帮助
I was trying to help.
我已告诉你 现实就是如此
I told you, it's what is.
我真的不能相信
I don't wanna believe that.
你觉得他们能找到麦可吗
You think they found Michael?
他们应该能找到他吧
I mean, they probably have found him.
或许吧
Yeah, probably.
走吧
Let's go.
我的腿 我的腿 痛死了
My leg! My leg! Jesus! God damn it!
别出声 别乱动
Shut up. Shut up. We got you. We're getting out.
- 他的小腿都烂了 - 好惨
- His leg is shredded. - Shit.
向导呢
Where's the guide?
- 那死小子落跑了 - 该死 我算是知道什么叫合作了
- The son of a bitch is gone! - Fuck him. I know the coordinates.
没他我们到不了河边的
We're not making it to the river with him.
你能不能闭嘴
Would you shut the fuck up? Come on and tie his leg.
- 把他的靴子脱了 - 不
- Take off his boot. - No!
让他穿着 让我来 我们是医生
Leave his boot on. Let us in here, we're doctors.
- 我需要一把刀 - 这儿 这儿有
- I need a knife. - Here, here, here.
噢 妈的 妈的 干
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
- 他撑得过去吗 - 我也不知道 组个担架来
- Is he gonna make it? - I don't know. Make a stretcher.
散开
Spread out!
守住占领点
Take the point.
你听见了没
Hear that?
他们在找我们
They're tracking us.
他们追踪我们身上的味道
They're on our scent.
- 转身 - 你要干什么
- Turn around. - What are you doing?
- 转 转 - 好
- Just move. Turn. Turn. - All right.
你们两个朝东南方去河边
I want you two to head southeast to the river.
船在那等着
And the boat will be waiting.
如果找不到 沿着河岸走 我会找到你们
If it's not there, you keep following the shoreline till I find you.
你呢
What about you?
我会照顾自己 把定向地雷给我
I'll be all right. Give me that claymore.
- 现在开一枪 - 什么
- Now fire off a shot. - What?
开一枪 快
Fire off a shot!
你一点能做到
You're gonna make it.
快走
Go! Go!
- 快走 快走 - 快 快
- Come on! Come on! - Move! Move it!
- 快点 - 来了 来了
- Let's go! - I got you. I got you!
抓紧 抓紧
Grab it! Grab it!
- 我不行了 - 起来
- I can't. - Get up!
我不行了
I can't.
来 来
Come on. Come on.
- 趴下 趴下 趴下 - 什么 那是什么
- Down, down, down. - Wait. What is it? What? What?
混帐王八蛋 你看
Son of a bitch. Look.
怎么回事
What is it?
噢 天啊
Oh, God!
噢 该死
God damn.
没胆的孬种
You gutless fuck! You fucking pussy!
该死的孬种
Motherfucker.
胆小鬼
Gutless fuck!
再揍我啊 瘪三
Come and have a go at me, you lady-boy cunt!
来啊
Come on, you… Fucking have a go at me!
该死 你们这帮畜牲 天啊
Fuck… You fucking… Do something…
他妈的畜牲
Fucking Jesus!
噢 我的天
Oh, God.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
我们什么都做不了
Nothing we can do.
我的天
Oh, God.
不
No.
克伦反抗军来了
The Karen rebels.
麦可
Michael?
麦可 麦可
Michael? Michael?
麦可
Michael?
麦可 麦可
Michael! Michael!
麦可
Michael!
没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
- 我们去帮他们 好吗 - 好
- Go help them, okay? - Okay.
（蓝波之家）